Meet Philip Marlowe. The toughest private eye who ever wore a trench
coat, slapped a dame and split his knuckles on a jawbone.
The Big Sleep is a crime, mystery film directed by Michael Winner.
Private eye Philip Marlowe investigates a case of blackmail involving the two
wild daughters of a rich general, a pornographer and a gangster.
Philip Marlowe, played by Robert Mitchum.
Charlotte Sternwood, played by Sarah Miles.
Lash Cansino, played by Richard Boone.
Camilla Sternwood, played by Candy Clark.
Agnes Lazelle, played by Joan Collins.
Joe Brody, played by Edward Fox.
The Big Sleep is a 1978 neo-noir film, the second film version of
Raymond Chandler's 1939 novel of the same name.
The picture was directed by Michael Winner and stars Robert Mitchum in his second film portrayal of
the detective Philip Marlowe (following Farewell, My Lovely three years earlier).
The cast includes Sarah Miles, Candy Clark, Joan Collins and Oliver
Reed, and features James Stewart as General Sternwood.
The story's setting was changed from 1940s Los Angeles to 1970s London.
The film contains material more explicit than what could only be hinted at in the 1946
version, such as drug addiction, homosexuality, pornography and nudity.
Mitchum was age 60 at the time of filming, far older than Chandler's 33-year-old Marlowe (or the
1946 film's 38-year-old Marlowe, played by Humphrey Bogart, who was 45 at the time).
The film explores themes of daughter, based on novel
or book, general, blackmail, remake.
The tone is mind_bending.